## Juan Ayala

# Full Stack UX/UI designer

Full Stack UX/UI designer with over 3 years' experience creating apps for technology and design businesses and over 5 years of graphic design experience.

Skilled in Graphics, Web Design, Design Thinking Methodologies, Coding, Branding and Advertising.

#### Skills

Adobe Suite, InVision, Marvel, Balsamiq, Sketch, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, MS Office, Photography and 2D/3D animation.

#### Contact

- in www.linkedin.com/in/jp-ayala
- ayalajuano@gmail.com
- **©** 083-3034668
- 7 Millbourne Avenue, Drumcondra, D09 RR29, Ireland.
- https://ayalajuano.github.io/
- Bē www.behance.net/ayalajuano

### Education

Dublin Institute of Graphic Design Dublin, Ireland. Sep 2016 - May 2018

BA in Graphic Design

Nueva Esparta University Caracas, Venezuela. May 2008 - Jun 2012

 BS in Business Administration and Graphic Design

## Languages

Spanish Native, English C1 Portuguese B2, French A2, Italian A2.

#### Hobbies

Languages, networking, technology, photography, music, travelling.

## Work Experience

## **UX/UI** Designer

ALTV Media, Dublin, Ireland

Dec 2017 - Feb 2020

- Completed market research, personas creation and user journeys for apps in line with the client's target audience.
- Carried out app designs by following the design thinking method (sketches, wireframes, prototyping, A/B testing and final app design).
- Created responsive web apps using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript based on client briefs.
- Delivered app redesigns focusing on streamlining existing designs and improving usability.
- Key projects include: Dugout and National Broadband Ireland.

## **UX/UI** Designer

#### Meebler, Dublin Ireland

Sep 2016 - Jul 2017

- Designed and developed a complete new company website as part of the product modification and relaunch.
- Expanded the company's branding and identity from only a logo to cover all graphic elements including motifs and iconography.
- Contributed to developing an understanding of the user personas and journeys by taking part in team workshops.
- Designed a prototype app for both the internal and external user interfaces for submission into the Dublin Tech Summit 2017.
- Carried out QA testing of prototype app ensuring user flow was intuitive.

## **UI** Designer

#### Marketplace Connectors, Dublin, Ireland

May 2016 - Sep 2016

- Created responsive and intuitive designs for the Connect.IO platform for mobiles, tablets and desktop.
- Designed marketing collateral, infographics and videos to support the company's business development initiatives.
- Created photographic marketing material by leading photo sessions with the key company personnel for social media and the company's website.

#### Career Break

Freelancing, travelling, learning new languages.

Sep 2013 - Apr 2016

## **UI** Developer

#### Servicios Netosfera, Caracas, Venezuela

May 2013 - Aug 2013

- Advised clients on the development of their company's branding.
- Designed and developed corporate websites including updates to existing websites under a maintenance agreement.
- Prepared captivating designs for client's branding and marketing material.

## Graphic Designer

#### Super Eventos, Caracas, Venezuela

Sep 2011 - Aug 2012

- Designed impactful proposals and presentations for marketing events.
- Created interactive applications to showcase the event highlights for client's senior managers. Clients included Samsung and Coca-Cola.
- Designed promotional materials for events in line with client's branding and identity.